[MUZICĂ]
In classification the concept of
over-fitting can be even stranger than it
is in regression because here we're not
just predicting a particular value.
A price for house or even whether
reduce positive or negative but
we're often asking probabilistic
questions like what is the probability
that this review is positive?
So let's see what over-fitting means with
respect to estimating probabilities.
So as you remember from
the previous modules,
we talked about the relationship
between the score on the data, so
that's w transpose h, which we raise
from minus infinity to plus infinity.
And actual estimate for probabilities,
the probability of y equals plus
one let's say given its input x and
w as a sigmoid applied to
the score function w transpose h.
So that's the model we're working with and
if you remember as we see over 50 we
see w's becoming bigger and bigger.
This coefficient's becoming bigger and
bigger and bigger and
bigger which means that w
transposed h becomes huge, massive,
and that pushes us either if it's
massively positive to saying that
the probability is exactly one,
pretty confident they are one or
if they're massively negative,
they're confident they are zero.
So over-fitting in classification,
especially for
logistic regression can have
very devastating effects.
It can yield this really
massive coefficients which push
w transposed h score
to be very positive or
very negative, which puts the sigmoid
to be exactly 1 or exactly 0.
And so not only are we over-fitting but
we're really confident
about our predictions.
We think that this is
exactly a positive review
when we should more assertive about it.
So let's observe how
that shows up the data.
Let's go back to the simple
example that we had before where
we're just fitting a function,
a classifier using two features,
number of awesome's and number of awful's.
Let's say the coefficient
of awesome is +1,
and the coefficient of awful is -1,
and we have an input.
Two awesome's, one awful.
If you look at the difference between the
number of awful's and number of awesome's,
you have one here cause there's
one awesome within these awful's.
And so
the actual score that we get is one,
which means the estimated probability
Of a positive review is 0.73
is probability review is positive.
And I can live with that you know,
I have a review, it has two awesome's,
two things are awesome about
the restaurant were awesome, it's more of
a half probability of being a positive
review but not a lot more than half.
If I take the same coefficients, nothings
changed, the same input, but I apply these
coefficients by two Now I have two
awesome's and, sorry, two awesome's
one awful still as input, but the
coefficients are plus two and minus two.
Now the curve becomes steeper.
And so if I look at the same point where
the difference between awesome's and
awful's are at one, and
I look at my predicted probability.
Now I've increased it tremendously.
Now I see the probability of
positive review, is about 0.88.
I'm even more confident that
the same exact review is positive.
So that doesn't seem as good,
88% chance that it's positive.
But let's push the coefficiencts up more,
let's say that the coefficient of
awesome is plus six and
the coefficient for awful is minus six.
Now if I look at the same point.
The same import.
The same difference between awesome's and
awful's and I push that up.
I get this pre scare result it says that
the probability of being
a positive root 0.997.
I can't trust that.
Is it really a case of 0.997 probability?
The review of two awesome's and
one awful is positive?
That doesn't make sense.
So as you can see, we have the same
decision boundary still crossing at 0.
The coefficients are just
getting a bit bigger every time.
But my estimated probability of the review
becomes steeper and steeper more and
more likely.
Which is another type of over 50 that
we observe in logistic regression.
So not only the curves with them weird and
wiggly but
the estimated probabilities become
close to zero and close to one.
So let's look at our data set and
see how we observe the same,
the same effect right there.
[MUZICĂ]