[MUSIC]
So far when we talked about gradient
decent and gradient ascent we had the step
size parameter a that we
just assumed to be given.
Let's talk a little about how to
choose that step size parameter a.
Spoiler alert this is really hard,
it requires lots of tuning and
one of the annoying things
about gradient assent approach.
We're going to talk about a few heuristics
of how we might want to do that.
Now one of the most important things
you can do when you're trying to
pick the step size is to build
what's called a learning curve,
and this is what I'm
showing you right here.
So in the x axis we have
the iteration number
which in our gradient algorithm we call t.
So this is one iteration,
two iterations, and so on.
And then for each iteration, or
maybe you do this every ten iterations or
every few iterations.
Here I did it every one iteration.
You measure the log likelihood
over all of the data.
So this is basically the log of
the product over my data points
one through N of
the probability of YI given XI
and the current estimate at
iteration T of the parameters.
So this is your quality metric.
want to measure the quality metric after
each iteration, after each update.
And you'll see that the quality
metric is getting bigger and
bigger in a pretty smooth way,
which is nice.
We start from a lower number,
about minus 37,000,
remember we talked about
these numbers being negative.
And then they go up and up and up as we
deal with, if we had more iterations.
And this for
a particular step size value, eta equals
right here which is equals
to ten to the minus five.
So it's a relatively small step size, and
that's how we get this curve over here.
Which is, looks pretty decent,
and it keeps going up.
Now, how'd I end up with eta 10 to the -5?
Basically what we're going to do is try
a bunch of different parameters data and
try to hone in to a good one.
And to understand what can happen with
a parameter data which is too small or
too large, let us observe those
lending curves, and by observing them,
you get an idea, get a sense of
a possible behavior to observe in
your data and
then use that to pick a good parameter.
Now, for 10 to the minus 5,
I called it a little small,
because as you can see, the curve is
still going up after 50 iterations.
So maybe one thing to think
about is that we need to do
more than 50 iterations in this case.
So that's another thing to observe,
not only are we picking eta,
we're thinking when are we done,
what's the stopping criteria.
And here the curve is still going up so
we should keep going.
Now, what would happen if you
pick a eta that's too small?
So now let's observe two curves.
The top one, is the one we just observed,
where the eta has value 10 to
the -5 and the green curve is,
eta's ten times smaller.
Eta is 10 to the -6.
And what we observe there's
two smooth curves, but
the 10 to the -5 goes up much quicker and
gets to a higher likelihood value.
So here again we're plotting l of wt.
Getting to a higher likelihood value
then the one to ten minus six, but
that line six is still going.
It's just a really small step size so
it's climbing up the hill.
That we have in really, really, really,
really small steps, small steps,
small steps, so it's going to take a long
time to get to the top of the hill.
Eventually will, but
it's going to take a long time.
So you see, if you were to try this plot.
You see the tension minus five is probably
a better parameter than tension minus six.
So that's a good thing so
you got time two minus five its
looking pretty good maybe you want to
try something a little bit larger so
if you try something larger you're taking
bigger steps towards the top of the hill.
So here I'm comparing what happens if I
try eta step size 10 to the minus five,
as opposed to this other
sine curve which is eta
being 1.5 times 10 to the minus 5.
So here we're picking
a parameter which is 50% larger.
And this is really interesting,
really interesting behavior.
We've observed this
behavior a lot in practice.
So this early phase,
here so you get some early
oscillation,but once you start getting to
the beginning it doesn't do something so
good.
But once you start getting towards
the top of the hill you see that towards
the end the larger parameter
values tend to make more progress.
So smooth, so this has, Zion, has smooth,
faster progress at the end.
And you see that it's starting to get
even higher values of likelihood,
so higher quality.
Remember that higher here is better.
As we get more iterations.
So it's kind of interesting,
if a parameter is bigger, not too big or
bigger, you might see some
oscillations in the beginning,
but it tends to smooth out and do well.
So then you might say okay 1.5 times 10
to the minus five seems pretty good let's
try something even a bit larger.
[MUSIC]