[音楽]
So, here's the rule of
thumb of how you can pick
the learning step size eta when
you're doing graded descent.
Unfortunately, there's some theory
behind things they might want to do,
but it's kind of hard to
apply those in practice.
Here's the most practical
thing you can do.
You try several values of the parameter,
exponentially spaced between each other.
Like 10 to the minus 4, to 10 to
the minus 6, that's exponentially spaced.
And the goal is plot the learning curves
to find an eta that is too small.
So the curve is moving too slowly,
too slowly, too slowly.
And then you find an eta that is too
large, these wild oscillations and
it's diverging even.
And now we have a big value and
a small value,
and then, you can try values in between,
again, exponentially space.
Spaced and pick one that leads to
the best training likelihood.
And that's how you do it.
Pretty simple heuristic, but
it's basically something that you
will have to do if you're
implementing this from scratch.
Now note that so
far we've looked at only fixed step size.
Every iteration we used
the same step size,
like ten to the minus five, everywhere.
Here's an advanced step.
In theory and often in practice,
it's good to pick step sizes
that decrease over iterations.
So in the beginning,
you take really big steps because
you're very far away from the optimum.
But towards the end they
take much smaller steps,
smaller steps to just hone
in to that perfect value.
So if you imagine you
take the contour plots,
in the beginning you're taking
big steps like this, but
to be able to get to the optimum, you
take very little steps towards the end.
And that's how you kind of hone
in to the optimal here w hat.
So what is that equation for
the step size look like?
There may be various
ways of defining them.
I'm just going to give you one pretty
practical example, which often works well.
So you pick a step size that depends
on the iterations of iteration t.
You're going to use eta t.
And the way you're going to
write it is by writing eta 0.
Some constant that you tune using the same
kinds of ideas that are described above to
find the minimum, the maximum,
the range in between.
And then you divide that
by the iteration number t.
以上です
So iteration one use eta 0.
Iteration two use eta 0 over 2.
Iteration three it is 0 over 3,
over 4, over 5, and so on.
And that way the step size keeps getting
smaller and smaller and smaller.
So this is an advanced step for the
applications that we're going to discuss
in this module, constant step
size will do just fine for you.
But, for kind of more advanced settings,
you might use a decreasing step size.
[音楽]