[ӘУЕН]
We've now seen how to compute the log
likelihood, but before continuing,
we're going to have to express
the probability of y = -1
because we've only so
far expressed the probability y = +1.
This is still part of that very,
very optional PhD level only
derivation of the gradient.
So this is only for
those who are really interested.
We need to take a moment to derive
what is the probability that y = -1
if the following up here is
the probability that y = +1?
So let's just derive that.
So the probability that y = -1 given x and
w
is just one minus the probability
that y is equal to +1 given x and w.
This is just because
probabilities add up to one.
So, let's plug that in,
that's one minus one times one plus
E to the minus W transpose h(x).
I just plugged it in with
the definition of probability of y=+1.
Now, if we multiply both elements
by 1+e to the -w transpose x,
we get the probability
that y is equal to -1 is,
so I'm multiplying both terms
by 1+e to the -w transpose h(x).
So the one is 1 + e to
the -w transpose h(x) and
then you get 80 minus one.
So the whole thing here simplifies to e
to the -w transpose h(x) divided by
1+e to the -w transpose h(x).
Pretty cool.
Very simple.
Here we go.
[ӘУЕН]