[MUSIC]
So, this is going to be pretty simple.
It'll be similar to the document
retrieval notebook that we did to find
documents that were similar to Barack
Obama, to Clinton, to Beckham, and others.
So, let's go ahead and
what we're going to do is train
a nearest-neighbors model for
retrieving images using deep features.
So this is going to be pretty simple.
And we're gonna call it the, knn_model,
just like we did with document retrieval.
And when I use graphlabs
nearest neighbors toolkit,
and we're going to code the create
verb to actually create this
nearest-neighbors model, and
just like in the nearest-neighbors model,
we're going to give it some data, so
in this case it would be my train data.
I'm going to tell it what features to use.
So the features that I'm going to use are
going to be exactly those deep features.
And then just as a reminder,
you can give it a label ID.
So the label here, we're going to use
the image ID, which will then allow
us to go back and find the images that
correspond to the nearest neighbors.
[MUSIC]