[MUSIC]
So now, let's talk about how we can
use these metrics of precision and
recall to compare our different algorithms
that we might think about using.
And to do this we can draw something
that's called the precision recall curve.
And let's start by talking about what
these curves are gonna represent.
And what the curves are gonna represent
is for a given recommender system,
what I'm gonna ask you to do is I'm gonna
ask you to vary the threshold on how many
items that recommender system
is allowed to recommend to me.
So I'm gonna rank, for example all
the baby products on Amazon and
I'm gonna allow you to recommend
just one or two or three and so on.
And so
that's a threshold that you're varying.
And that's going to trace out this curve.
And what would this curve look like for
optimal recommender where we only
recommend products that I like?
Well, what's the precision when
I recommend just one product?
Well we know that's a product I like and
so my precision,
my world is just that one product, and
I liked it, so my precision is one.
And what's my recall though?
If I have let's say,
ten items that I liked and
I've only uncovered one, it's one-tenth.
And likewise,
as I'm increasing the number of
items I show,
my precision always stays at one.
I'm only recommending products I like,
but my
recall is increasing because I'm covering
more and more of the items that I liked.
So eventually, we will hit this 1, 1 spot.
So the optimal precision recall
curve is this line here.
Okay, but let's talk about what
the curve might look like for
another more realistic recommender.
I guess before that, let me just annotate
that this is our optimal recommender.
Now, let's go on to look at perhaps
a more realistic recommender and
what it would look like.
Okay, well, the first product we
recommend might not be a product I like,
or it might be, so it's gonna start
somewhere on a precision axis.
And then eventually at some point
when I vary the threshold enough,
at some point hopefully,
I will recommend some product I like.
So both precision and
recall are gonna go up.
Then what tends to happen is we
add a product that I don't like.
So at that point what happens,
well my recall stays exactly
the same because I haven't recovered any
more of the items that I'm interested in.
But my precision drops because now
I'm looking at a larger world,
a larger set of green squares.
So my precision goes straight down but
my recall stays the same,
and you tend to get these very
jaggedy looking curves or
you get these drops in precision, then
these increases in precision and recall.
And I'm gonna draw it,
it won't be completely accurate here, but
it looks kind of like that.
Typically something like this
would be a precision-recall curve.
Okay, so this is an example
of a more realistic system.
This is another recommender
system compared to our optimal.
Okay, so now, that we know how to draw
these precision-recall curves, we can talk
about comparing our different algorithms,
how do we know which one is best?
Well, we know that we'd like precision and
recall both to be as large as possible and
what's the best that it can be?
We talked about the optimal
recommender being that curve.
But then when we look at our other curves
which are these jaggedy looking things,
one doesn't have to
strictly dominate another.
They might do different
things at different points.
So one curve is not necessarily,
let me actually erase that and
do it in a different color so
it's a little bit clearer.
It's not that one is always
gonna be better than the other.
Maybe we have another one going here.
So in this case,
how do I think about comparing these
different algorithms, and
choosing which one is best?
Well like I said, we want precision and
recall to be as large as possible but
one thing we can measure to
compare these is in general,
which one is doing better than the other
and what's a way to think about that?
Well, we can think about
the area under the curve.
So we can look at for example,
all this area under this blue curve.
And we can compare that to, for
example the area under the green curve,
and
I can say which area is larger.
And that is one proxy for
which recommender system
is doing a better job.
So that's this point here,
that a metric we can use is
something called area under
the curve which measures
exactly what I drew below.
But you might not care about how
the recommender system is doing
across all possible
performance situations.
Instead, you might be in a situation
where let's say you have a website and
you know based on the real estate of that
page, how many items you can display.
So maybe you can display ten different
items to recommend to the user or
you know what the attention span
of the users are in general.
And you wanna limit how many products
you recommend to 20 products or
something like this.
So in those cases,
where you specifically know how many
products you're gonna be recommending,
you care about what your precision is
at that number of products recommended.
Because you want that precision
to be as large as possible for
the constraint of recommending
that number of products.
And so these are two examples of
metrics you might use to compare
between different algorithms using
this notion of precision and recall.
[MUSIC]