[MUSIC]
So to this point though,
we've assumed that we know all
these Lu user topic vectors.
So we can stack them
up into this L matrix.
And we know all the movie topic factors.
So we put them altogether
in that R matrix.
And then, we multiply the two
together to get this big prediction
of readings that every user
would give to every movie.
But important thing here is the fact that
we don't actually have this information.
We don't have these features about
the users, or about the movies.
So instead, what we're gonna do is we're
gonna flip this problem on its head.
And we're gonna try and
estimate these matrices, this L and
R matrix, which is equivalent to
estimating these topic vectors, or
feature vectors, for every user and
every movie based on our observed ratings.
So these matrices, or
these collections of topic vectors,
are the parameters of our model.
So going back to the regression
module that we had, we talked about
models and their associated parameters in
thinking about estimating
those parameters from data.
So this is a very similar notion.
So we have data.
What are our data?
In this case,
our data are our observed ratings.
So those are the black squares.
And our parameters are these user and
movie topic factors.
Okay, so what we're gonna do is we're
gonna estimate each of these from
our observe reading.
So only using these black cells,
we're gonna try and
estimate these L and
R vectors and resulting matrices.
So how are we gonna do this?
Well, let's think of a metric for
fit just like we talked about
in the regression module.
If you remember,
going back to that module we talked about
something called residual sum of squares.
There we were talking about a house.
It had some set of features.
And then,
[COUGH] we had weights on those features,
those weights were our parameters.
And we were predicting
somehow sales price.
And then, we compared with the actual
sales price, and we looked at
the square of that difference, and we
summed over every house in our data set.
Well, in this case,
the parameters of our model are L and R.
And our prediction,
our ratings hat is gonna be <Lu,
Rv>, this notation of doing this
element wise product in summing.
And that's our predicted rating.
And then,
our observed rating is Rating(u,v),
and what we're gonna do is
look at that difference,
the difference between
our observed rating and
what we're predicting with our parameters
Lu and Rv, and we're gonna square them.
And we're gonna say our residual sum
of squares of our parameters L and
R is equal to this, and then we're gonna
sum over all movies that have ratings.
So we're gonna include all u,
v pairs where [BLANK_ AUDIO] rating,
let me use u' to v' to distinguish it
from the specific u and
v example I gave here.
So we're gonna add in all u' v' pairs.
Where rating u' and
rating v' are available.
And where are these available?
They are the black squares.
Just remember this picture here.
Okay, so what I'm doing is I'm
taking a given L matrix and
R matrix, I'm looking at my predictions.
So I'm looking at, and I'm gonna evaluate
how well I did on all these black squares.
So I'm looking at how well the L and
U that I'm using fit my observed ratings.
And then,
when I want to go to estimate L and R,
just like when I wanted to estimate the
weights on the regression coefficients in
that housing value prediction problem,
I search over, in this case, all
the user topic vectors and all the movie
topic vectors, and find the combination of
this huge space of parameters that
best fits my observed ratings.
And so, the reason this is called a Matrix
Factorization model, so that's really key.
This is called a matrix factorization
model, because I'm taking this matrix,
and approximating it with
this factorization here.
But the key thing is the output of this,
is a set of estimated parameters here.
And, unfortunately, I've just written
over this very, very, very key point.
So I apologize for that.
Let's pause for a second, so
that you get the writing.
And now, I'll just say in words this next
animation is saying that there are a lot
of very efficient algorithms for
doing this factorization.
And we're gonna talk about them in great
extent in the recommender systems,
or matrix factorization course later on.
But then, okay, so
very efficient algorithms for
computing these estimates of L and R.
How do I form my predictions?
How do I fill in all these white squares,
which was my goal to start with.
Well, I just use my estimated L hat u.
And R hat v.
And I form my prediction
just as we described
when we assumed that we
actually knew these vectors.
Okay, well, matrix factorization
is a really, really powerful tool.
And it's been proven useful on
lots of different applications.
But there's one limitation, and that's
a problem that we talked about a little
bit earlier of the cold-start
problem where this model still can't
handle this problem of what if we
get a new user or a new movie.
So that's the case where we
have no ratings either for
a specific user or a specific movie.
So that might be a new movie that
arrives or a new user arrives.
So this is a really important problem.
And one that, for example,
Netflix faces all the time.
How do we make predictions for
these users or movies?
[MUSIC]