[MUZICĂ]
We've discussed error and
accuracy as ways to evaluate a classifier.
Now, it's very important to
understand the accuracies or
errors that you're actually
getting from your classifier.
I really think deeply about
whether those are good errors or
good levels of accuracy in your situation.
So for example,
one of the common mistakes you might make
is to say how good is my
classification at all?
When you build a classifier,
the first baseline comparison it
should do is against random guessing.
So for example, if you have a binary
classification problem like is this
sentence of positive or
negative sentiment, then just random
guessing is gonna give you 50% accuracy
on average, so you better beat 50%.
If you have k classes, so for
example, if you have 3 classes.
You're gonna have a random
guessing accuracy of 33%.
For 4 classes it would be 25%, for
k classes it would be 1 over k.
So at the very least it should
beat random guessing really well.
Because if you don't then your
approach is basically pointless.
Now, even beyond beating random guessing,
truly think deeply about whether you
classify, even it if looks really good,
is it really meaningfully good?
So for example, suppose you have a span
predictor that gets 90% accuracy.
Should you go brag about it?
Is that awesome?
Well, it really depends.
So the case of spam, not so good,
because in 2010 data shows that 90%
of the emails ever sent were spam,
90% of the emails.
So if I just guess that every email
is spam, what accuracy do I get?
90%.
This is a problem where this is what's
called majority class prediction so
its just predicted classes most common.
And it can have amazing performance in
cases where there's what's called class
imbalance.
One class has much more
representation than the others.
Spam is much more representative
than regular good emails.
And so, you have to be very cautious and
really look at whether you have class
imbalance when you try to figure
out whether your accuracy is good.
And of course, this also beats,
this approach also beats random guessing,
if you know what majority class is.
So you should always be
digging into your problem, and
understanding really thinking about
the predictions you're getting and
whether that accuracy is really
meaningfully good for your problem.
So ask yourself questions like,
is there class imbalance?
How they compare against baseline
approaches like random guessing,
majority class and
really fancier things than that.
And most importantly,
think about your application and
ask yourself, what is a good enough
accuracy to make my users really happy?
So, in spam filtering, if your accuracy is
not that good, then there'll be important
messages going to the spam folder,
and that could be a really bad thing.
[MUZICĂ]