[ӘУЕН]
We talked about a lot of application
domains where we see recommender systems,
but now let's talk about how we
actually build a recommender system.
And there are lots and
lots of approaches for
performing these types of recommendations
and let's discuss some of them.
And the first Level 0 way we might
think about recommending products
is just based off of
the popularity of each product.
And this approach is actually really
popular on things like news sites.
So, for example, New York Times has this
list on the side of the website that says,
the most popular articles, and it's
sorted by different topics, for example,
the most emailed articles.
So here when we think about
recommending articles to other readers,
we're just sorting the articles
by how often they were shared
by other readers on New York Times.
So this can work fairly well.
I might actually discover an article that
I'm interested in using this type of
approach.
But one disappointing thing about it
is it completely lacks personalization,
because all the recommendations
are based off of the entire
population of New York Times readers out
there, which is actually pretty diverse.
So instead, I would, of course, love to
have a method that knew a little bit more
about me and my interests to
recommend news articles to me.
So let's try and add in a little
bit of personalization using
a classification model where we're going
to use features of both the products and
the users to make our recommendations.
And this classification model is going to
look exactly like the classification model
that you're just learning from Carlos,
where there you guys were using
classification to do sentiment analysis,
but here, we're going to
use this model to classify whether
a person likes or does not like a product.
Okay. Okay. So this classification model
is going to take in features about
the user, features about
the past purchases of that user,
features about the product that we're
thinking about possibly recommending,
as well as potentially lots of other
features that we can talk about.
And we're going to shove all these
features into our classification model,
and it's either going to spit out,
yes, I believe this person is going to
like this product or, no,
I don't think they're going to like it.
Well, this type of classification approach
has a lot of things going for it.
So first it can be very personalized.
We're using features of the user as
well as the user's purchase history.
And, in addition,
this model can capture context.
So, for example,
we can take into consideration the time
of the day, what that person just saw.
So, for example, maybe I'm much
more likely to purchase a textbook
during the day or home products at night.
And one other really nice thing about this
approach is the fact that it can handle
a very limited user history.
So, for example,
let's say I'm a user on Amazon and
I haven't purchased
many items in the past.
So for a lot of approaches, there might
be a lot of ambiguity about what I
might be interested in or not, but if you
have information about me, such as my age,
that alone can be very predictive
of what I might like or not like.
But this approach has limitations as well.
And one of the important limitations is
the fact that these features that we're
talking about that can be so informative
about the products that we're going to
potentially like or
not might not be available.
So, for example,
you might not know my age.
You might not know my gender.
And the list goes on and on.
And, likewise, for a product, you might
also have either missing information or
very poorly written product descriptions,
especially on Amazon where you have lots
of people on there selling
different products.
The quality of that information
might be pretty low.
So often what we actually see is something
that's called collaborative filtering,
which we're going to talk about next,
can actually work better than this
type of classification approach.