[MUSIC]
So, we've learned that deep
neural networks are really cool,
high accuracy tool, but they can be
really hard to build and learn, and
require lots and lots of data.
So next, we're gonna talk about
something really exciting.
Which is called deep features,
which allow you to build neural networks,
even when you don't have a lot of data.
So, if you go back to our data
image classification pipeline,
where we start with an image, we detected
some features, or other representations,
and we've had that to a simple classifier,
like a linear classifier.
The question here is can we somehow
use the features that we learn
through the neural network?
Those cool ones at the corners, edges and
even faces, to feed that classifier?
So can we do something a little different?
The idea here,
that you have deep features,
is something called transfer learning.
So transfer learning is pretty old idea,
that's been around for quite a while, but
had a lot of impact in recent years
in the area of deep neural networks.
So the idea here is, I train the neural
network in a case where I have lots and
lots of data.
So for example, in a task of
differentiating cats versus dogs.
And I learned that eight layers,
16 million parameter complex new network.
And I get great accuracy in
the task of cat versus dog.
Now, the cool thing is to say, okay,
what if I have a little bit of data,
not tons of data for new tasks,
let's say I am detecting chairs and
elephants and cars and
cameras in hundreds of categories.
Can we somehow use the features that we
learned in cats versus dog to combine for
simple classifier and feed that and get
great accuracy on this 101 new categories.
That's the idea of transfer learning.
The features I learned from cat
versus dog get transferred to provide
accuracy in the new task, which is
detecting elephants, cameras and so on.
To understand transfer
learning deep neural networks,
let's revise the idea of what
a deep neural network might learn.
So here's a deep neural
network of cat versus dogs.
And let's say that we have really good
accuracy there for that task, task one,
cats versus dogs.
If you look at the last few layers, they
really focus on the cat versus dog task.
They're very specific.
It kinda like I showed you, there's
an example where there was a detection of
colors inside that last layer.
Now the ones in the middle
are much more general.
They can represent things like corners and
edges and circles and
squiggly patterns and things that can
really generalize from the cat versus dog
task to this more general
101 categories task.
So let's talk about how we can deal
with second task, 101 categories.
So we learn deep neural network for
the cat versus dog can apply for Task 2.
Now, if you think about it,
this end piece of the neural network
is very specific to cat versus dog.
So it's not that useful for
detecting chairs perhaps.
So what we can do is chop off the last
few layers, the last layer lets see it
in the network and keep the weights
fixed for the first several layers.
Because those are good those
detected good features.
This last layer with a simple linear
classifier which is simple, so
I can just train in the little bits
of data that I have about chairs,
cars, elephants, and cameras.
So going back to the example
that we described earlier,
where we had three layers.
The first layer detected
diagonal edges and edges.
The second one detected
squiggly patterns and corners.
While the third one was about colors and
faces,
we now can use those layers for new task,
but we need to be a little careful.
Layer 3 might be too specific but
layers 1 and 2 can be quite useful.
So now that we learned about
transfer learning the concept,
let's review that deep learning pipeline,
but using these deep features.
So I'm gonna start with some labeled data,
not tons, just a little bit is enough.
And then I'm gonna extract
features using that
deep neural network
just like we described.
I'm gonna split this data set into
training and test of validation set.
I'm gonna learn the simple
classifier like linear classifier,
support vector machines, simple things.
And as I validated,
since it's a simple classifier,
there's not many parameters to tune.
Pretty easy to do.
Can be learned with little data and
do quite well.
And in fact, we see an application
off the application where this idea
works extremely well, and is exactly
the idea that I showed you in the demo,
the beginning of the module when I
showed you how to buy new dresses.
We didn't have lots of data about visual
description dresses, but we used something
that was trained on imagenet to provide
you with a good dress shopping experience.
Now, you may ask,
how general are these deep features?
Can they really be used for
interesting, extremely unusual tasks?
Well, actually, you will be surprised.
In fact, let's talk about trash.
[LAUGH] A company called compology.
It's a pretty interesting company.
They're trying to reinvent
how trash collection is done.
Normally, the trash truck goes from house
to house, from business to business, and
collects trash on a regular basis,
every day, once a week, and so on.
They wanna change that and
optimize the path of trucks and
how trash is collected to minimize
the amount of time spent.
And the way they do that is by
installing cameras on trash cans
to figure out what's in there and
how full it is.
Well we don't have tons of labeled data of
how images look for full trash cans, but
when they did this, use deep features and
a little bit of training data from humans,
marking the depth of trash cans
to learn a trash detector,
and be able to optimize the path of
trucks, in order to better serve.
So decrease the amount of time
trucks need to collect garbage.
So deep features are useful even for
garbage.
[MUSIC]